[Music]
ok ladies and gentlemen the most
important Physiology question of all
time which type of bicep curl is better
the incline curl like so leaning on an
incline minute or the preacher curl now
I know every one of you are out there
thinking I know the answer Andi it's so
obvious and I do too which is all I'm
gonna tell you do I know the answer
instead I'm going to focus a little bit
more time on learning some cool
physiology all right so again I know you
know the answer but we'll do this five
minutes real quick Cockermouth
physiology and then you can show that
your friends who don't know the answer
and then they'll figure out which type
of bicep curls better so let's get to
that what I'm talking about here the
major will difference between the
incline and the the preacher curl is the
amount of stretch the muscles put on and
I'm not talking about like stretching
your bicep don't go do a bunch of bicep
stretches I'm not talking about
stretching your hamstring before you
workout I'm talking about putting it on
an acute stretch
all right so understanding the
difference in terminology here is gonna
help you get through this next couple of
minutes all right
so now muscles can only shorten by about
50% of their resting length what's that
mean so if the muscle is already
shortened about one joint it can't
contract forcefully over the other so we
know that some of the biceps cross the
shoulder joint we know all of them cross
the elbow joint that's the primary point
right so if I am shortened about one of
my joints
I can't contract fully over the other
one this is another way of saying a
muscle that crosses multiple joints
can't produce force over one when it's
shortened about the other this is why
it's critical if you ever take any
certification especially like the NSCA
is cscs which I strongly encourage
they're gonna really hammer you on which
muscles cross multiple joints it's
really important you should be able to
understand which calf of your cows small
calf muscles cross both the knee and the
ankle because some of them don't
some they all cross the ankle but some
of them
same thing with the hamstrings the quads
the elbow flexors and extenders all
right that's really that's really
important because of this point so we'll
do the calf example because it's the
most common one that shows up on
basically every CSCS exam ever I almost
guarantee you get this question if you
take that exam so take a look at like a
seated calf raise so here's what you
notice we know the soleus crosses the
ankle joint we know the gastroc crosses
ankle joint they both turn into the
Achilles tendon right and they and
certain the bottom of your foot but the
soleus starts like Midway up your calf
you can see the image there the cast
rock crosses behind the knee joint
so they both contribute to you sticking
your ankle out which is called plantar
flexion but the gastroc is also involved
in knee flexion interesting so when we
do a seated calf raise and we flex our
knee we know the gastroc really can't
contract forcefully over the ankle
because it's bent about the knee so a
seated calf raise is not a bad exercise
but it is pretty much a soleus isolator
now that's not bad or good it's
fantastic if for example you're saying
man I really need to do some ankle or
calf work but my knee is kind of get
irritated every time I do standing calf
raises you might know oh actually maybe
something's going on for gastroc so let
me put you in this seated position Oh
pain goes away
yeah entirely okay then we know exactly
what's going on or if for any other
reason you feel like you need to isolate
the soleus the opposite could be an
example though if I do a standing calf
raise like you've seen the second
picture you can know you're gonna get
activity from both the soleus and the
gastro so there's never it's never a
right or wrong thing it's always will
understand what's happening and then
deploy appropriately all right so our
answer to our original question again
for your friend who couldn't figure it
out by now which one is better the
incline the preacher curl well I'll give
you a couple of examples say you need to
work on your biceps in general but
you're complaining of shoulder pain
which one would you use I'm not telling
it you better figure that out yourself
another example say using the bicep curl
as a part of a general physical
development program well in that
particular case
probably the incline is a little bit
better because we're putting the muscle
on more stretch it's letting it cross
both of its shoulder joins us so we're
gonna get the most even amount of work
as opposed to the preacher curl which is
going to take the shoulder joint out of
it which is going to let you isolate one
muscle and particularly now I will give
bonus points probably the England class
that can tell me which of those muscles
we're talking about so with is the bicep
curl or the bicep muscle that's going to
cross the elbow joint only and not
really and be implicated in the flexion
of the shoulder in fact I think it's a
quiz question spoiler alert another
example if you're trying to train to get
jacked so say you're an amateur
bodybuilder are competing in a show and
you identify a specific part of your
bicep that's behind well then maybe you
can address it because you now know okay
if it's this part of my advice if I put
it in this position but if it's that
part of my bicep I put it in that
position so hopefully you have an answer
to how to optimize your price up but
really more importantly you understand
the importance of how when muscles cross
multiple joints what that does to their
contraction you hopefully could do the
same thing with your hamstrings so
examples here would be doing an RDL
using the hamstrings that cost across
the hip joint
but the hamstrings also cross the knee
joint so what happens and how does that
change in our deal when you give us a
really big bend in your knee versus when
you go very stiff and extended me it
changes it it will change where you're
sore out I promise you I know a lot of
you that have done hinging stuff will
feel that hinging and your knees bent
but have you ever done it with a really
aggressively locked out neat try it that
way it's different okay the same thing
happens at your quad by the way think
about a seated leg extension versus a
squat or the hip is flexed and extended
versus flex the entire time one of those
quad muscles can't let me work see the
hamstring curl tricep pushdowns versus
tricep here right putting the most long
stretch or not alright so hopefully you
learned something there I really
appreciate all you know the stuff here
with YouTube to make it bigger and all
that stuff so do all the stuff you know
what to do Thanks
[Music]